A Guide to the Edward H. Peeples, Jr. Papers, n.d., 1915, 1920s-2005
Virginia Commonwealth University, James Branch Cabell Library
- Professional and Biographical 1950s-2000 (Box 1-7)
  - Virginia Commonwealth University (VCU) - Education Advocates Program, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Virginia Commonwealth University Free University - Jewish Community Center Program, n.d., 1986, 1989-1990 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - "You Don't Have to Be White to Be Healthy - But it Helps" by Peeples - manuscript, correspondence, outline, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 37)
- Broad Subject Areas n.d., 1950s-2000 (Box 8-18)
  Series is arranged in sub-series: Sub-series A: African American Studies Program, VCU (n.d., 1968-1973, 1996); Sub-series B: Camille - Hurricane Camille (1957, 1969-1970, 1990s); Sub-series C: Cancer Rehabilitation and Continuing Care Program, MCV/VCU (1973-1980); Sub-series D: Minority Health Advisory Committee (n.d., 1989-2000); Sub-series E: Multiculturalism (1950s-1990s); Sub-series F: Preventative Medicine (n.d., 1959-1996); Sub-series G: Prison Rape (n.d., 1960s, 1974-1988); Sub-series H: Project W.A.R.M.T.H. [Willing and Able Resource Mother Team Health] (n.d., 1985-1990); Sub-series I: Race (n.d., 1940s-1990s); Sub-series J: Richmond City Commission on Human Relations (1979-1987); Sub-series K: School Inequality (1960s); Sub-series L: Violence Prevention (n.d., 1990-2000); Sub-series M: VCU Violence Prevention Project (n.d., 1992-1995)
  - African American Studies Program (AAS), VCU, n.d., 1968-1973 (Box 8)
    - Articles and newspaper clippings, 1968-1970 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - African American Studies Program at VCU, Part I, Edward Peeples, [Includes materials related to the founding of the program and a class taught by Vincent Wright and Peeples called "Sociology of Racism" 1969-1971 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - African American Studies, Part I, Edward Peeples, (copies) 1969-1971 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - African American Studies, Part II, Alan Briceland, n.d., 1968, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - African American Studies, program, October 4, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - New Course Proposals, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Survey of Afro-American Studies 202, 1970-1973 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Camille - Hurricane Camille 1957, 1969-1970, 1990s (Box 8)
    - "The Aftermath of Camille's Aftermath: A Preliminary Report" by Peeples (drafts, notes, misc.), 1969 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - The Agnes Disaster and Federal Response, Correspondence and notes, 1969-1974 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - "Forgotten People: Little Known facts about Disaster relief in a Democracy" by Peeples (Draft), 1969 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Government Proposals and Acts, 1970-1973 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - "How Hurricane Violence Forces Integration in Mississippi," JET Magazine, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - "Human Adaptation to Disaster," 1957 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - "In the Wake of Hurricane Camille: the Federal Response to a Hurricane," 1969 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Institute on the Human Dimensions in Disaster Relief," VCU School of Social Work, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - "Madame Camille - A Parting Word" - Memorandum, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - National Conference on the Status of Health in the Black Community (Publication), 1971 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Newspaper clippings and articles (copies and originals), 1969-1970 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Newspaper clippings and articles (copies), 1969-1970 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1971-1990s (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Testimony prepared for Special Subcommittee on Disaster Assistance, U.S. Senate, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Cancer Rehabilitation and Continuing Care Program, MCV/VCU, 1973-1980 (Box 8-9)
    - "Development and Utilization of Rehabilitation and Continuing Care Resources and Services" Semi-annual Report, Dec. 1976 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - "A System for the Rehabilitation Outcomes in Cancer Patients: I Overview" by Peeples (et al) - drafts and correspondence, 1977-1979 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - "A Study of Consensus on Rehabilitation Goals in a Sample of Cancer Care Practitioners" by Peeples, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - "Projects Associated with the Cancer Center", n.d. (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Program Evaluation, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence, 1975-1979 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Graphs, tables and figures, 1974-1980 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Outcome and Evaluation, 1975-1977 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Program Evaluation (original), 1979 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Program Evaluation (original prints and negatives for the publication), 1979 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Reports (one of two), 1970s (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Reports (two of two), 1970s (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Study of Project Objectives (including patient interviews and out comes), 1974 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Minority Health Advisory Committee, n.d., 1989-2000 (Box 9)
    - "African American Health and Well Being" Dr. Rudolph Wilson, c. 1998 c. 1998 (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - Brochures from the Virginia Department of Health, Project Immunize Virginia, Hispanic Committee of Virginia, Monacan Indian Tribe, Inc., c. 1990s c. 1990s (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - Conference, 1996 (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - Correspondence, data, proposals, newspaper clippings, 1990s (Box 9, Folder 31)
    - Data Subcommittee - Violence and Intentional Injury, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 32)
    - Eastern Shore of Virginia, n.d., 1989, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 33)
    - Edward Peeples selected contributions, 1994-1995 (Box 9, Folder 34)
    - Flyers, 1992-1993 (Box 9, Folder 35)
    - Healthcare Summit Proceedings, VA Dept. of Health, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 36)
    - Heart Memo (newsletter of the national Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute), Winter 1993 (Box 9, Folder 37)
    - Initial Progress Report, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 38)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1993, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 39)
    - Meeting Minutes and Agendas, 1991-2000 (Box 9, Folder 40)
    - Member list, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 41)
    - Minority Health Fact Sheet, c. 1990s (Box 9, Folder 42)
    - Minority Health Work Plan July 1996 to October 1997 (Box 9, Folder 43)
    - Presentation, 1998 (Box 9, Folder 44)
    - Reports, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 45)
    - Second Progress report - Summary of Town Meetings (draft), November 1994 (Box 9, Folder 46)
    - Second Progress report - Summary of Town Meetings, May 1995 (Box 9, Folder 47)
    - Selected contributions (by Edward Peeples), 1994-1995 (Box 9, Folder 48)
    - Small Area Population Estimates for the State of Virginia, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 49)
    - Virginia Minority Health Data Report, 1998 and 1999 1998 and 1999 (Box 9, Folder 50)
    - Women's Health Status in Virginia, Report to the Virginia Department of Health, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 51)
  - Multiculturalism 1950s-1990s (Box 9-10)
    - Articles, newspaper clippings, miscellaneous publications, 1989-1992 (Box 9, Folder 52)
    - Human Relations Area Files, Yale University, 1988-1991 (Box 9, Folder 53)
    - Intergroup Relations, 1950s-1980s (Box 9, Folder 54)
    - Intergroup - Robbers Care Experiment, by Peeples, 1956-1984 (Box 9, Folder 55)
    - Miscellaneous Materials, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 56)
    - Multicultural Education, 1980s-1990s (Box 9, Folder 57)
    - Multicultural Education (teaching materials?), 1980s-1990s (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Multicultural Glossary, by Peeples, 1968, 1990-1991 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Multiculturalism Seminar by Peeples, 1997 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Multicultural Task Force (Medical College of Virginia), c.1987-1991 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Papers on Islam, 1990-1991 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Socioeconomic Issues - articles and publications, 1968, 1971-1972, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - "This Side up Please" - newspaper clipping, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - VCU Multicultural Institute - Community through Diversity, 1991-1992 1991-1992 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - "Working with Multicultural Effectiveness in Human Services" (handouts used by Peeples), c. 1980s (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Preventive Medicine n.d., 1959-1996 (Box 10-11)
    - Department of Preventative Medicine Departmental Budget, Senate Budget Amendment Form, Preliminary Self Study report - Master of Public Health Program - Reviewer copy, 1993-1995 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Department of Preventative Medicine Activities, n.d., 1959-1963, 1980, 1983, 1985-1988, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Department of Preventative Medicine and Community Health, n.d., 1975-1976, 1986-1988, 1990, 1992-1995 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Graduate Program in Public Health, Draft #1 "Working papers" by Peeples, April 1987 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Historical and Organization of Home Medical Care in Richmond, Virginia, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - "Information Related to the feasibility of a Masters of Public Health Program at Virginia Commonwealth University" by Peeples, March 1987 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - "In-Patient Services: A Report to the Virginia Appalachian Health Services (VAHS), November 1969 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Masters of Public Health - class schedules, course announcements, 1993-1995 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Masters in Public Health Program Curriculum Competencies, n.d., 1989, 1990, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Masters in Public Health Curriculum Committee Handouts, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Masters of Public Health History - Curriculum, Faculty Listings, Commencement programs, n.d., 1993-1996 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Masters of Public Health History - Proposal for Program, student interest letters, curriculum draft, 1982, 1986-1995 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Masters in Public Health Program - class and faculty lists, pamphlets, advising guidelines, n.d., 1991-1995 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Masters of Public Health Program Task Force, 1986-1987, 1995 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Masters of Public Health Program Task Force - Proposal for Graduate Program in Public Health, September 1987 (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Masters of Public Health Program Task Force Statement of Readiness, 1987, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - Medical College of Virginia Schedule of Classes, 1992-1995/ Virginia Commonwealth University Schedule of Slasses, 1995 1992-1995 (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - Miscellaneous Documents - Medical Care Survey, publications, poster, 1967-1969, 1986-1988 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Proposal for Master of Public Health by Peeples, March 1988 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Richmond Home Care study Final Report, 1966 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - University Health Promotion Activities Inventory Survey, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Virginia Board of Health meeting, 1988-1989 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Working papers on the "Evidence in Support of a masters of Public Health Program at Virginia Commonwealth University", August 1987 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Written works of Frederick J. Spencer (Chairman of Department of Preventative Medicine and Associate Professor of Preventative Medicine), 1966-1968, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Prison Rape n.d., 1960s, 1974-1988 (Box 11)
    - Articles and newspaper clippings, 1976-1988 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Bibliographic References, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence (misc.), 1978-1982 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - First World Congress of Victimology, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Lecture (by Peeples), n.d. (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Newspaper clippings regarding Peeples, 1976-1980 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Male Rape, (book with introduction by Peeples), 1980-1982 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Male Rape, Citations and reviews, 1982-1987 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Male Rape, Correspondence, 1978-1982 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Radio and television interviews, 1997, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Stop Prisoner Rape, Inc. and Stephen Donaldson (Victim / Activist), 1993-1997 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Stress Impact Study - Correspondence, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Stress Impact Study - Methodology, 1960s-1970s (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Stress Impact Study Technique n.d. (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Virginia Commonwealth University (VCU) - Research in Action, 1978-1979 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Prison Rape Cases - Michigan Case, 1974-1982 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Prison Rape Cases - Michigan Case (FBI), 1979-1980 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Prison Rape Cases - Fairfax Co, Virginia Case, 1975-1977 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Prison Rape Cases - Mecklenburg, Virginia Case, c. 1980 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Prison Rape Cases - Prince William Co., Virginia Case, 1975-1976 (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Prison Rape Cases - Prince William Co., Virginia Case, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Prison Rape Cases - Richmond, Virginia Case, 1979-1980 (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Prison Rape Cases - Cases - Correspondence, 1977-1988 (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Prison Rape Cases - Prison Rape and other injury cases - Summary Materials n.d. (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Project W.A.R.M.T.H. (Willing and Able Resource Mother Team Health) n.d., 1985-1990 (Box 12)
    - Project W.A.R.M.T.H., n.d. (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Project W.A.R.M.T.H. (one of three), 1985 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Project W.A.R.M.T.H. (two of three), 1985 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Project W.A.R.M.T.H. (three of three), 1985 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Project W.A.R.M.T.H., 1986 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Project W.A.R.M.T.H., 1987 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Project W.A.R.M.T.H., 1988 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Project W.A.R.M.T.H., 1989 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Project W.A.R.M.T.H., 1990 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Project W.A.R.M.T.H., Promotional materials [audio cassette, flyers], n.d. (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Project W.A.R.M.T.H., Proposal for Resource Mother's Program, (one of four) 1985 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Project W.A.R.M.T.H., Proposal for Resource Mother's Program, (two of four) 1985 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Project W.A.R.M.T.H., Proposal for Resource Mother's Program, (three of four) 1985 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Project W.A.R.M.T.H., Proposal for Resource Mother's Program, 1985 (four of four) 1985 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Project W.A.R.M.T.H., Resource Mother's List, 1985-1985 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Race n.d., 1940s-1990s (Box 13-14)
    - American Friends Service Committee - Prince Edward County - Correspondence, 1961 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - American Nazi Party and George Lincoln Rockwell, c. 1965-1968 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - American Nazi Party - newspaper articles, 1963-1985 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - American Nazi Party - Letter from member George Ware to Peeples, 1966 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - "American Racism: Implications for Social Work" by Howard Arnold, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - "The Anxiety of Being Japanese-American" New York Times Magazine article, 1985 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - "Are the Races Different," 1982 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Articles, 1940s-1950s (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Articles, 1960s-1970s (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Bibliographies by Peeples, n.d., 1971, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - "The Birmingham Bombing", New York Times article, 1983 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - The Bobbs - Merrill Reprint Series in Black Studies, (Articles reprinted from 1919, 1965, 1966, 1968) n.d. (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Book reviews, book lists, 1964-1975 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Charlottesville Activist Coalition flyer "How does Virginia Support Racism?" c.1970s (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - "The Consequence of Racial Isolation in Public Schools," 1967 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Dating, Family, Marriage - articles, references, c. 1971-1974 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - "David Duke: In His Own Words" Anti-Defamation League, brochure, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Department of Public Works - Richmond, Virginia, n.d., 1977, 1984 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Desegregation "The Deep South Says Never" S aturday Evening Post article, 1957 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Directory of Civil Rights and Human Rights Organizations in Virginia, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Drew, Charles Dr. publication from First Unitarian Church, Richmond, Virginia, c. 1968 (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Economic Status of Negroes: In the Nation and in the South by Vivian Henderson, c. 1964 (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - Ethnic name studies by Peeples, 1965-1995 (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Ethnic Notions - announcement for documentary video, c. 1987 (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - "Education and Intergroup Attitudes: Moral Enlightenment, Superficial Democratic Commitment, or Ideological Refinement?" 1984 (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - Fair Housing News Exchange, newsletter July-August 1965 (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - "Final Report - John Kenneth Morland, Scholar and Advocate for Racial Justice: In His Own Words, Virginia Foundation for the Humanities and Public Policy," submitted by Edward Peeples, June 30, 2002 (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - "Guineamen," Guinea, Virginia - newspaper clipping, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 28)
    - Hispanic Communities in the U.S., 1991 (Box 13, Folder 29)
    - "How Southerners Gave up Jim Crow" by John Shelton Reed and Merle Black, 1985 (Box 13, Folder 30)
    - "A Jewish View on Segregation" brochure, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 31)
    - Kirkpatrick, James - articles, editorials, letter from Bishop Walter Sullivan to Peeples, 1960s-1980s; 1985 (Box 13, Folder 32)
    - Knights of the Ku Klux Klan (KKK), pamphlet, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 33)
    - Ku Klux Klan - article, 1957 (Box 13, Folder 34)
    - Ku Klux Klan - "The Klansman who Quit Hating" - article, 1982 (Box 13, Folder 35)
    - Ku Klux Klan - Lynching photos, 1980 (Box 13, Folder 36)
    - "A Longitudinal study of Blacks' Perception of Race Relations: A Study of Village Blacks in a Southern Area," c. 1970s (Box 13, Folder 37)
    - "Major Racial, Ethnic, and Other Culturally Differentiated Aggregates in the U.S." by Peeples, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 38)
    - Malcolm X, articles, newspaper clippings, 1963-1966 (Box 13, Folder 39)
    - "Material Opportunities in Public Education in the Commonwealth of Virginia: "A Study of Public School Property Differentials between the Races" by Peeples, 1962-1966 (Box 13, Folder 40)
    - Marsh, Henry L. III, letter and newspaper clippings (campaign committee), 1982 (Box 13, Folder 41)
    - Melungeons - newspaper clippings, 1997 (Box 13, Folder 42)
    - Miscellaneous newspaper clippings, 1960s (Box 13, Folder 43)
    - Miscellaneous newspaper clippings, 1970s (Box 13, Folder 44)
    - Miscellaneous newspaper clippings, 1980s (Box 13, Folder 45)
    - Miscellaneous newspaper clippings, 1990s (Box 13, Folder 46)
    - Miscellaneous scholarly sources, articles, bibliographies, student paper, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Museum in a Trunk A Black Heritage Exhibition, announcement, 1987 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Native Americans, "The Indians of Virginia" 1976 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Native Americans, miscellaneous publications, c. 1960s-1980s (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Native Americans, "The 20-points Position Paper", 1972 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - "The Negro's Future in the South," US News and World Report article, 1963 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1984 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - A Perspective on the Prince Edward County School Issue, by Peeples, [original, on onion skin paper] 1963 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Plessy vs Ferguson, 1896 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - "Prince Edward County" article by Peeples and J. Rupert Picott in Journal of Phi Delta Kappan, May 1964 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Private Schools in Virginia - Correspondence, data, newspaper clippings, and notes, 1958, 1963-1965, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Race and health articles, 1960s-1970s (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - "Race and Mental Health in Mass Society," by Seymour Leventman, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Race and Nursing, 1950s-1960s (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - "Race, Biology, and Health Care: Reassessing a Relationship", 1990 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Racist Cartoon "Hambone" by J.P. Alley, 1934 (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Racist chain letter, VCU campus, 1989 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - "Race in America: The Conservative Stand" by William J. Simmons, Congressional Record - House, 1960 (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - "Recent Incidents of Racist Violence in the Southern States," 1979-1981 (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Richmond, newspaper clippings, 1981-1990 (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Richmond Council on Human Relations, 1963-1964; 1971-1973 (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - Richmond, Virginia, Memo on community tension from Assistant City Manager, J. Wilson, 1980 (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - The Rockwell Report, May 1965, Nov.-Dec. 1966 (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - "Social Status and Community Participation of Negroes in Two Communities of the Deep South", 1972 (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - "The Statute of Limitations on Nazi Crimes" by Harvey Cox, 1965 (Box 14, Folder 25)
    - "Student Remembrances of the Yale School in China (Yali) During the War of Japanese Aggression" by Liu Zhengbi and Morland, 2002 (Box 14, Folder 26)
    - "Such a Simple Act" by Peeples, Style Weekly, Feb. 20, 1990 (Box 14, Folder 27)
    - Text of the Proposed Voting Rights Act, printed in the Richmond News Leader, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 28)
    - "Toward the Promised Land" by Dalmas Taylor, 1984 (Box 14, Folder 29)
    - "Unmasking Martin Luther King. Jr. the Deceiver," pamphlet, c. 1960s (Box 14, Folder 30)
    - U.S. Department of Commerce (1990 Census), 1991 (Box 14, Folder 31)
    - U.S. Commission on Civil Rights (speech by Peeples), 1979 (Box 14, Folder 32)
    - "Verbal Attitudes, Overt Behavior, and the Influence of Social Constraint in Interracial Behavior," 1966 (Box 14, Folder 33)
    - Virginia - newspaper clippings, 1957-1969 (Box 14, Folder 34)
    - Virginia - newspaper clippings, 1970s (Box 14, Folder 35)
    - Virginia - newspaper clippings, 1980s (Box 14, Folder 36)
    - Virginia - newspaper clippings, 1990s (Box 14, Folder 37)
    - Virginia -notes by Peeples, miscellaneous articles, 1960s-1980s (Box 14, Folder 38)
    - "Why do Stereotypes Persist in the Age of Space Travel" by Peeples (Box 14, Folder 39)
    - The Winrod Letter, 1962 (Box 14, Folder 40)
    - "White Guilt" by Shelby Steele, 1990 (Box 14, Folder 41)
    - White Supremacy Groups - articles, flyers, n.d., 1962, 1969, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 42)
  - Richmond City Commission on Human Relations 1979-1987 (Box 15)
    - Annual Human Relations Award, 1984 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Richmond City Ordinances, 1985 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1980-1981 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1983 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1984 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1985 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Director - Janice Mapp - newspaper clippings, 1979-1980s (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Gay and Lesbian Survey, 1983-1987 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Gay and Lesbian Survey - articles, c.1980s (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Gay and Lesbian Survey - newspaper clippings, 1983-1987 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Member and contact list, 1980-1984 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous, 1979-1985 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Newsletters and flyers, 1980-1984 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Richmond Airport Commission Grievance, 1983 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Richmond Airport Commission Grievance - newspaper clippings, 1983-1985 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Richmond City Code of 1975 1975 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Richmond Movie Entertainment Survey - newspaper clippings, 1982-1983 (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Richmond Movie Entertainment Survey, 1980-1981 (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Richmond Movie Entertainment Survey - Correspondence, 1981-1982 (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - "A Study of Supply and demand in the Inner City: The Case of Movie Entertainment in Downtown Richmond", 1982 (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - "A Survey of Perceptions of Civil Opportunity among Gays and Lesbians in Richmond, Virginia", 1985 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - School Inequality, 1960s (Box 15)
    - Miscellaneous newspaper clippings and documents, 1960s (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - Charts, Part I, 1962-1963 (Box 15, Folder 23)
    - Charts, Part II, 1962-1962 (Box 15, Folder 24)
    - Charts, Part III, 1962-1963 (Box 15, Folder 25)
    - Southern School News, Nov. 1962-Dec. 1963 (Box 15, Folder 26)